# Kushal Honnappa, Curriculum Vitae

( + 1 7575593495 | Kushal.h1999@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/kushal-h

S: Google Scholar | R<sup>6</sup> : ResearchGate

# Research Interests \_

Mission: My goal is to gain advanced knowledge in the field of Artificial intelligence and obtain

experience in the domains like ML, Deep Learning, NLP, Computer vision, and reproduce a

product that helps in the betterment of society.

Interests: Artificial Intelligence (AI); Machine Learning (ML); Deep Learning (DL); Natural Language Processing

(NLP); Computer Vision; Django

# **Education**

PhD., Computer Science

Old Dominion University

**B.Tech.**, Computer Science Engineering

PRESIDENCY UNIVERSITY 7.37/10 CGPA

2022 - Present Virginia, USA 2017 - 2021 Bengaluru, India

# **Professional Experience**

# **Software Developer**

Medilenz Innovations Private Limited

September.2021 - August,2022

Bangalore, India

Worked as a software developer over the technologies that include flask framework, Django framework, and NLP for text processing, summarizing the documents, NER operation to extract clinical and medical data. classifying the medical data using image processing techniques and histogram. Have built a web portal which have 150 users.

# **NLP Research intern**

February. 2020 - July. 2021

Avkara Technologies Private Limited

Jaipur, India

Worked as a research intern where I have the responsibility to research to mask the received voice data to unrecognizable voice by hiding private information and implement it. I have explored techniques like Bert, LSTM till now, and now working on other techniques to get better accuracy. The main purpose of this masking is to maintain anonymity by the user in our application.

# Django Rest Frameworks Developer Intern

September.2020-February.2021

Avkara Technologies Private Limited

Jaipur, India

Worked as a Django Rest Frameworks developer intern. I had the responsibility to work on the backend part of the mobile application using DRF. This application is used for the mental health department where people can express their problems anonymously.

Research Intern June. 2019 - August. 2019

Xcelerator.ninja

Bengaluru, India

Worked as a research intern, I have researched on emerging technologies. I explored the AI and its techniques. I worked on the database project.

# **Projects**

AgriDoc Project link

In this project, I have created a web application that predicts the occurrence of diseases in the plant and recommends suitable remedies to solve them. Here I have trained 5 different models and deployed them using the Django framework.

# **Sentimental Analysis**

**Project link** 

I have done an end-to-end sentimental using NLP and CNN here I have trained for a 100k tweet dataset. I have used Django to deploy the project

Mask Detection Project link

I have done a project object detection project which detects using a live camera where the person is wearing a mask or not

Shopping website Project link

This is a project where I have developed a website using Django as a framework and developed a web application.

Credit card reporting of fraud

Project link

In this project, I have trained data with different types of ML algorithms and selected the best algorithms, and deployed it in the Django framework to make predictions.

Face detection Project link

This is a project which identifies the face of a person and expresses the name. I have used transfer learning in it.

# Courses

Deep	Learning	<b>Specialization</b>
------	----------	-----------------------

A Coursera specialization courses with 5 sub courses certificate link

**DeepLearning.Al TensorFlow Developer Specialization** 

A Coursera specialization courses with 4 sub courses certificate link

Al Foundations for Everyone Specialization

A Coursera specialization courses with 3 sub courses <a href="mailto:certificate link">certificate link</a>

**Natural Language Processing Specialization** 

A Coursera specialization courses with 4 sub courses <a href="mailto:certificate link">certificate link</a>

**IBM Applied AI Specialization** 

A Coursera specialization courses with 6 sub courses certificate link

**IBM Data Science Specialization** 

A Coursera specialization courses with 9 sub courses certificate link

**Applied Data Science Specialization** 

A Coursera specialization courses with 4 sub courses certificate link

**Key Technologies for Business Specialization** 

A Coursera specialization courses with 3 sub courses certificate link

**Architecting with Google Compute Engine Specialization** 

A Coursera specialization courses with 5 sub courses <u>certificate link</u>

STATS FOR DATA SCIENCE

This is where I learned live "statistics requirement for data science" certificate link

Machine Learning A-Z™: Hands-On Python & R In Data Science

The Udemy course which thought on ML with hands-on experience certificate link

**Deep Learning A-Z™: Hands-On Artificial Neural Networks** 

The Udemy course which thought on Deep Learning with hands-on experience certificate link

**Modern Natural Language Processing in Python** 

This Udemy course which though me about NLP with the hands-on projects certificate link

# Research papers

# AgriDoc: Classification and Prediction of plant leaf diseases

<u>Publication link</u>

This paper gives a brief explanation of the project which helps to detect and identify the diseases accordance in with the plants in the agriculture field. The paper is published in Turkish Journal of Computer and Mathematics Education (TURCOMAT).

# **Smart Automation Attendance System using Neural Networks**

Publication link

The paper describes how we can automate attendance in Universities or at the workplace just by clicking multiple pictures at the desired place. This research is inclined towards Neural network

#### Masking Private User Information using Natural Language Processing

Publication link

In this paper, we have written about a mobile application that we have built and the integration it with NLP to provide complete anomaly by masking user's private data. This paper is published in the IJARIIT journal.

#### Reverse Recommendation: without user details

**Publication link** 

This is the next version of Masking Private User Information using Natural Language Processing where a recommendation system is included. The users get recommended posts by analyzing their current posts.

# **Crop Infection Detection using YOLO**

Publication link

This paper gives a deep explanation for identifying the infected plant by its leaf using the YOLO object detection algorithm.

# A Survey on Role of Emerging Technologies in implementing smart Agriculture Preprint li

This is a survey paper that explains how advanced technologies help farmers to increase production and creates smart farming.

# **Extracurricular activities**

# Speaker for tech talk (AI)

Was a speaker for the tech talk on "How AI and Machine Learning are helping to solve the World's most difficult problems" at KARPAGA VINAYAGA COLLEGE OF ENGINEERING & TECHNOLOGY, Chennai.

Research Project certificate link

Attended webinar on 'Funding opportunity for research projects' which by conducted by chief principal scientist, CSIR- National AeroSpace.

NLP workshop certificate link

Attended Natural language processing (NLP) workshop for 5 days organized by Reva University

#### Machine Learning & its Recent Trends

certificate link

I attended machine learning and its trend webinar which was associated with IEEE and organized by Presidency University

# Google 30 days

Google 30 days challenge and won swags by google as an appreciation on completing it.

# Paradigm (model)

Participated in 'Paradigm (model)' competition (a computation where we have to show a real working project), where we built home automation system using Arduino board, which was on 15-02-2019 which was conducted on presidency.

#### Code Knack

Participated in 'Code Knack' (a code debugging computation) competition on 15-02-2019 which was conducted by Presidency University.

# **Skills**

- > Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Natural Language Processing, Computer Vision.
- > Django Web Framework, Django Rest Framework, Flask
- > TensorFlow (Framework)
- > PostgreSQL, SQLite, MySQL
- > Python, C, Java
- > Data Structures, Algorithm
- > Windows, Linux (Ubuntu) OS
- > Docker, Git

# **Personal Details**

Date of Birth: 21/04/1999

Sex: Male

Nationality: Indian

# **Declarations**

I hereby declare that the information furnished above is true to the best of my knowledge. I do hereby declare that the above particulars of information and facts stated are true, correct, and complete to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Location: VA, USA Kushal Honnappa